

DOUGLAS WHITE

Web Application Developer

CONTACT

512.293.1045

6801 19th Street #63 Lubbock TX 79407

www.douglaswhite.app

SKILLS

NODE, JAVASCRIPT, HTML5, CSS

ANGULAR, IONIC

REACT

REACT

TYPESCRIPT

COP, FIREBASE, AZURE

SERVERLESS FUNCTIONS

SQL, NoSQL, MySQL

CI/CD, AUTOMATION, TESTING

★★☆☆☆ MATERIAL DESIGN, SASS, LESS

SCRUM, AGILE

LINUX, BASH

AAAAAA

GOOGLE WORKSPACE

REFERENCES

Available upon request

PROFILE

5+ years experienced Web Application Developer adept at engineering mobile first, responsive, and progressive web applications utilizing best in class JavaScript frameworks, NodeJS libraries, SDKs, and Restful APIs to design, develop & maintain sleek, beautiful user interfaces while also delivering fast, intuitive & optimized user experiences.

EMPLOYMENT

8/2014 – Present

ApsisTech, Lubbock TX

Web Application Developer

Develop, optimize & maintain mobile-first & responsive progressive web apps utilizing Angular, Ionic & React frameworks & TypeScript

Interface databases & restful APIs utilizing serverless functions as server-side logic facilitating reduced costs & optimized server responses

Implement Material Design, Ionic, Bootstrap & MaterialUI design systems for constructing a responsive, attractive, optimized & intuitive UI/UX

Setup databases utilizing Firestore, CosmosDB, Azure SQL, MySQL & MongoDB Implement GCP, Firebase & Azure cloud platform services providing global reach, optimization, storage, analytics, SEO & hosting

Employ Automation, CI/CD & unit test utilizing Firebase Analytics, Azure Pipelines, GitHub Actions, Travis CI/CD, Karma & Jest

Integrate Node libraries & SDKs providing animations, steppers, charts, data-tables, eCommerce, visualizations, document & image management

Deploy hybrid native functionalities including push & SMS messaging, text-to-speech, geolocation and image capture built with Capacitor & Cordova

Engineer Google Workspace services including automation, bots, functions & AppSheet apps

8/2021 – 12/2021 **NCQA, Remote/Washington D.C.**

Web Application Developer

Designed, developed & optimized a prototype & MVP which enabled analysis of client hospital's measures data enabling better CMS reimbursements utilizing React, MaterialUI, TypeScript & Node libraries

Interfaced healthcare data APIs, FHIR/HL7 Excel spreadsheets, Azure SQL & CosmosDB databases utilizing Azure Serverless

Automated CI/CD, testing & deployment using Azure Pipelines & Azure Hosting Co-ordinated with teams utilizing Scrum methodology on Azure DevOps

8/2017 – 3/2020 RankFantasySports, Lubbock TX

Web Application Developer

Developed a mobile first, reactive progressive web app providing professional sports data analysis, data storage & lineup suggestions for players of daily fantasy sports competitions utilizing Angular 6, Ionic 3 & Material Design

Developed features including authentication, SMS, email & push messaging, form validation, Stripe eCommerce, an admin panel & a user administration panel

Implemented Google Cloud Platform services including Firebase Hosting, Serverless Functions, Firestore NoSQL database, and Firebase Analytics for optimization, real-time analytics & SEO

Integrated Node libraries to enable data tables, animations, charts & visualizations Interfaced with professional sports data APIs, weather data & Twilio APIs

2/2017 – 8/2017 Reagor Dykes Auto Group, Lubbock TX

Web Application Developer

Developed, maintained & optimized a VR & 360° spin progressive web app providing car inventory image management utilizing Angular 6, Ionic 3, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase Database, Firebase Storage, AppSheet & Cloudinary

Interfaced automobile marketing website APIs easing ad activation rollouts

Developed a web app utilizing Angular 6, Google App Scripts & Google Sheets which aggregated data providing lead to purchase attribution & real-time reporting of departmental revenues, costs & commissions

Education

Texas Tech University Lubbock, TX

1997 – 2000 B.S. Biology